<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">blockchain.lawyer</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-06-16T14:59:38+02:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Florian Glatz</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>fg@blockchain.lawyer</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Quiet Death of Ripple’s Codiu§ Project]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/death-of-ripple-codius/" />
  <id>/death-of-ripple-codius</id>
  <published>2015-06-14T00:00:00+02:00</published>
  <updated>2015-06-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Florian Glatz</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>fg@blockchain.lawyer</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;In order to understand the purpose that Codius was intended to serve in the wider Blockchain ecosystem, one has to understand the systemic limitations of the latter. For all the security that Blockchains are able to generate through their crypto-economic governance and incentive scheme, they suffer from inherent slowness when it comes to general-purpose computation, as well as from an inherent blindness when it comes to incorporating rich information about the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Codius’ complementary infrastructure decisions unfold their beneficial value to Blockchain-driven networks. Whereas Blockchains are good at delivering global consensus among thousands to millions of nodes, Codius’ solution is intended to deliver local consensus relevant only to specific individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about it over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@heckerhut/the-quiet-death-of-ripple-s-codiu-project-782c11a17c02&quot;&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/death-of-ripple-codius/&quot;&gt;The Quiet Death of Ripple’s Codiu§ Project&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Florian Glatz at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;blockchain.lawyer&lt;/a&gt; on June 14, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smart Contracts, Platforms and Intermediaries]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/smart-contracts-platforms-intermediaries/" />
  <id>/smart-contracts-platforms-intermediaries</id>
  <published>2015-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Florian Glatz</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>fg@blockchain.lawyer</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The platform model of today proves increasingly incompatible with some fundamental values modern societies hold dear, such as freedom of speech and the right to privacy. In case of platforms focused on economic trade, the very notions of private autonomy and freedom of contract are called into question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the invention of Bitcoin and the Blockchain, there is a new organizational model of how to reduce transaction costs effectively, while yielding vastly different results with regards to the protection of the fundamental rights affected by the deep diffusion of technology in modern day society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about it over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@heckerhut/smart-contracts-platforms-and-intermediaries-c3d30f5182a6&quot;&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/smart-contracts-platforms-intermediaries/&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts, Platforms and Intermediaries&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Florian Glatz at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;blockchain.lawyer&lt;/a&gt; on May 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Political Economy of Computing]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/the-political-economy-of-computing/" />
  <id>/the-political-economy-of-computing</id>
  <published>2015-05-13T00:00:00+02:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Florian Glatz</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>fg@blockchain.lawyer</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The political economy of computing takes into account the broader socioeconomic drivers of change in the relationship between humans and machines. Rather than focusing on the characteristics of the technology, on individual dealings with machines, or on organizational implications of technology, this perspective views technological change within the purview of sociohistorical developments, socioeconomic systems, legal and regulatory frameworks, environmental impacts, governance structures, and large–scale government policies and agendas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about it over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@heckerhut/the-political-economy-of-computing-7fffc75423a2&quot;&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/the-political-economy-of-computing/&quot;&gt;The Political Economy of Computing&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Florian Glatz at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;blockchain.lawyer&lt;/a&gt; on May 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modes of Contractual Governance in an On-Demand Service Economy]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/service-economy/" />
  <id>/service-economy</id>
  <published>2015-05-04T00:00:00+02:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Florian Glatz</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>fg@blockchain.lawyer</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;What has been dubbed the ‘Uber-for-X’ approach in the startup world, and the transformation to a on-demand service economy by scholars such as Harvard’s Yochai Benkler, turns out to be an interesting subject of study for economic organization theory. It is interesting to ask what modes of contract governance occur in those new-formed economic relationships between the platform provider (“Uber”) and its don’t-call-them-employees (“partners”) as well as its customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with Coase in 1937, a formal or semi-formal definition of the nature of the firm became the subject of scientific inquiry. Coase’ timeless contribution consists of two fundamental insights: the firm can be understood as the boundary where the price-mechanism of public markets is superseded by non-market-based hierarchical mechanisms of contract governance. To understand the nature of the firm therefore becomes the study of when it is preferable to vertically integrate some aspects of the firm’s production function with the means of a more complex contract regime than is characteristic of the spot contracts of classic exchange markets. The second insight is that the two alternate means of governance entail different costs under certain circumstances: e.g. a resource of which a constant supply is needed may be acquired more cheaply through a long-term supply contract rather than through regular spot exchanges on public markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conceptual framework laid down by Coase is powerful because immediately there come many different reasons to mind when a vertical integration of the firm’s external dependencies may prove cheaper in the long run. Technically, it is of secondary importance, if those reasons are modeled as transaction costs, as Coase did, or some other quantifiable or even non-quantifiable metric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of the rising on-demand economy, several interesting remarks can be made when mapped onto the Coasian model, starting with the concept of vertical integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about them over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@heckerhut/modes-of-contractual-governance-in-an-on-demand-service-economy-1833629f379b&quot;&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/service-economy/&quot;&gt;Modes of Contractual Governance in an On-Demand Service Economy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Florian Glatz at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;blockchain.lawyer&lt;/a&gt; on May 04, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are Smart Contracts? In search of a consensus.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/smart-contracts/" />
  <id>/smart-contracts</id>
  <published>2014-12-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Florian Glatz</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>fg@blockchain.lawyer</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Smart contracts are software that is executed in a rich and trustworthy computing environment.
They are contracts rethought for the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about them over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@heckerhut/whats-a-smart-contract-in-search-of-a-consensus-c268c830a8ad&quot;&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/smart-contracts/&quot;&gt;What are Smart Contracts? In search of a consensus.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Florian Glatz at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;blockchain.lawyer&lt;/a&gt; on December 11, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
